<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:postmedia="https://postmediavancouversun2.wordpress.com"
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Vancouver Sun</title>
	<atom:link href="http://vancouversun.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://vancouversun.com</link>
	<description>Vancouver News, Top Stories, Breaking Headlines &#38; Videos</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 04:35:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='vancouversun.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://vancouversun.com/osd.xml" title="Vancouver Sun" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://vancouversun.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
<image><url>https://postmediavancouversun2.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/vs-wordmark-250x39.png</url><title>Vancouver Sun</title><link>http://vancouversun.com</link><description>Vancouver News, Top Stories, Breaking Headlines &amp; Videos</description></image>	<item>
		<title>Did you ditch your rafts in the Cheakamus River? Squamish RCMP are looking for you</title>
		<link>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/did-you-ditch-your-rafts-in-the-cheakamus-river-squamish-rcmp-are-looking-for-you</link>
		<comments>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/did-you-ditch-your-rafts-in-the-cheakamus-river-squamish-rcmp-are-looking-for-you#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 03:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick Johnston]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Local News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RCMP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Squamish]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vancouversun.com/?p=799299</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It appears that a pair of rafts found unoccupied in Squamish on Sunday may belong to a group who were spotted exiting the&#160;Cheekye River. Squamish RCMP are calling the circumstances around the two rafts &#8220;concerning,&#8221; especially as this all happened hours after a man went missing after being swept into the fast-running Squamish River.&#160;That man [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It appears that a pair of rafts found unoccupied in Squamish on Sunday may belong to a group who were spotted exiting the&nbsp;Cheekye River.</p>
<p>Squamish RCMP are calling the circumstances around the two rafts &#8220;concerning,&#8221; especially as this all happened hours after <a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/search-underway-after-man-swept-into-squamish-river" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a man went missing after being swept into the fast-running Squamish River.</a>&nbsp;That man is still missing.</p>
<p>The two river-related incidents have also prompted police to issue a warning ahead of the coming Victoria Day long weekend.</p>
<p>According to a media release from Squamish RCMP, the two red and black rafts were found by Fisherman&#8217;s Park in Squamish, around 8 p.m., by a local resident, who were worried that someone had fallen into the river.</p>
<p>Police and Squamish Search and Rescue searched the area but didn&#8217;t find anyone.</p>
<p>During the search, several witnesses said they saw the trio, all wearing helmets, wet suits and lifejackets, navigating the Cheakamus Rivers but clearly having trouble with the raging waters. Searchers were also shown video that was taken of the group.</p>
<p>Later, a report suggested that three people seen getting out of the Cheekye River matched the description of the rafters seen in the video. The trio were seen loading a single raft into the back of a black pickup with a canopy.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Squamish RCMP and&nbsp;Squamish&nbsp;SAR have yet to locate the group and are looking for them or anyone who may know them to call the RCMP.&nbsp; The police need to assess their wellbeing and find out what happened during the incident,&#8221;&nbsp; Cpl. Sascha Banks said.</p>
<p>Given the hot weather expected over the next week and the ongoing snow melt making river flows evermore dangerous, police and other emergency services are warning people to use caution around the region&#8217;s rivers, especially with large crowds expected to descend on the area this weekend.</p>
<p><span style="font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Anyone with any information about the rafts or the rafters are asked to contact the Squamish RCMP at 604-892-6100 or to remain anonymous, call Crimestoppers at 1-800-222-TIPS, text 274637, or go to </span><a href="http://www.solvecrime.ca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.solvecrime.ca.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/did-you-ditch-your-rafts-in-the-cheakamus-river-squamish-rcmp-are-looking-for-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<postmedia:alexa><![CDATA[Did you ditch your rafts in the Cheakamus River? Squamish RCMP are looking for you. It appears that a pair of rafts found unoccupied in Squamish on Sunday may belong to a group who were spotted exiting the Cheekye River.]]></postmedia:alexa>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/122186081.jpg" />
		<media:content url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/122186081.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Integrated Homicide Investigation Team (IHIT) is investigating the discovery of a body early Friday in Coquitlam.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/698b81e98ea980c17ba35cb3f359980f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pjohnstonprov</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>David Black: It makes sense to build a refinery on the coast</title>
		<link>http://vancouversun.com/opinion/op-ed/david-black-it-makes-sense-to-build-a-refinery-on-the-coast</link>
		<comments>http://vancouversun.com/opinion/op-ed/david-black-it-makes-sense-to-build-a-refinery-on-the-coast#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 03:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harvey Enchin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Op-Ed]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vancouversun.com/?p=798963</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Our country must focus on three vital things: develop more good jobs, because many are disappearing; build new businesses that can be taxed, rather than increase the burden on existing taxpayers; and improve our physical environment while we do this. One obvious way to achieve this is to encourage &#8220;value-add&#8221; in the oil industry. Instead [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our country must focus on three vital things: develop more good jobs, because many are disappearing; build new businesses that can be taxed, rather than increase the burden on existing taxpayers; and improve our physical environment while we do this.</p>
<p>One obvious way to achieve this is to encourage &#8220;value-add&#8221; in the oil industry. Instead of exporting our crude oil to other countries, let’s process it here. Refineries can be built along B.C.’s coast employing large numbers of workers in good-paying jobs for decades and generating massive new taxes for our governments. (It is uneconomic to build export refineries in Alberta, which is why there are none there. All export refineries in the world are built on the ocean.)</p>
<p>Up to 85 per cent of a refinery’s annual operating cost is the price of the crude oil and the natural gas that it requires. Because Canada has large inexpensive reserves of these two resources consultants say that an export refinery near to the oil fields would be the lowest cost refinery on the entire Pacific Ocean. If we build it we can provide a substantial market for B.C. natural gas and help Alberta and Saskatchewan make 20 per cent more from their bitumen than if it is exported.</p>
<p>By keeping the refineries in our backyard we can also opt to decrease their CO2 emissions. Shipping diluted bitumen (dilbit) to any other country would result in far more global warming. A proposed refinery at Kitimat for example was going to save 23 million tons of CO2 emissions per year when compared to every other bitumen refinery in the world. That is equivalent to taking six million Canadian cars off the road forever. Some people were concerned about the proposal because they worried about increased emissions from within Canada. Should that be our concern or should we be working to reduce CO2 emissions globally?</p>
<p>Coastal refineries would also protect our ocean from dilbit. Dilbit differs from the conventional oil in Alaska-to-Washington tankers, which floats if spilled. There is only one published study that shows what would happen if there were a spill of dilbit in B.C.’s coastal waters. The study was thorough and overseen by Environment Canada, Fisheries Canada and Natural Resources Canada. It proves that because of all the grit in the ocean from B.C.’s glacial rivers, most of a dilbit spill falls to the bottom within three hours. There is no way to prevent that and no way to retrieve the dilbit so the ocean and fishery would be ruined for generations.</p>
<p>We are imposing carbon taxes on our oil industry. That made sense years ago when neighbouring countries were also promising to tax carbon emissions. However, it does not now because they did not. As a result companies worried about taxes are simply moving south of the border. Many, like Royal Dutch Shell, France’s Total, American ConocoPhillips, Norway’s Statoil, American Marathon Oil, and American Koch Industries have recently pulled out of Canada and increased production elsewhere. Carbon taxes are crippling our economy while accomplishing nothing to reduce global warming.</p>
<p>There is a better approach to reduce CO2 emissions in the oil fields. Governments should push for, and help support, pilot plants to test the use of cold solvent catalysts instead of hot steam and water, to melt the bitumen out of the sand formations. Most field emissions would then disappear.</p>
<p>One last point. Refineries are the source of most chemicals used by mankind. For that reason huge and fundamental industries locate near refineries to use the chemicals in manufacturing, scientific research and medical research. If we build large refineries we can capitalize on these associated opportunities too.</p>
<p>So, here are some common sense ideas to achieve the three vital needs:</p>
<p>Instead of punishing our oil companies with carbon taxes, and actually hurting our economy, let’s help them switch from using steam in the oilfields to cold solvent catalysts. Then let’s increase Alberta and Saskatchewan production in order to build more jobs, increase government tax revenues, and reduce CO2 emissions in other countries where emissions are high.</p>
<p>Instead of encouraging the oil industry to export our raw resources, let’s process them here and create several thousand new jobs in the refining and chemical industries, especially in B.C.’s northwest where they are badly needed, as well as more new taxes for governments.</p>
<p>Instead of shipping dilbit by pipeline to the coast, let’s transport dry inert bitumen by train. This will be less expensive because the rail lines across B.C. are in place and the distance is short. If and when a derailment occurs, backhoes can pick up the bitumen.</p>
<p>Instead of putting dilbit in tankers, let’s ship refined fuels that float and evaporate if spilled.</p>
<p>Instead of shipping dilbit to other countries, let’s build the greenest refineries on the planet in B.C., cutting the world’s CO2 emissions and producing the cleanest fuels on the globe. We would become a world leader in environmental refining, and other countries would follow.</p>
<p>Let’s use our common sense to improve things in Canada and the world. The added benefits would be economic growth, increased government tax revenues and a greener planet.</p>
<p class="p1"><em><span class="s1">David Black is chairman of Black Press Ltd. and founder of Kitimat Clean.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vancouversun.com/opinion/op-ed/david-black-it-makes-sense-to-build-a-refinery-on-the-coast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<postmedia:alexa><![CDATA[David Black: It makes sense to build a refinery on the coast. Our country must focus on three vital things: develop more good jobs, because many are disappearing; build new businesses that can be taxed, rather than increase the burden on existing taxpayers; and improve our physical environment while we do this.]]></postmedia:alexa>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2016/11/vancouver-bc-august-17-2012-david-black-owner-of-blac.jpeg" />
		<media:content url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2016/11/vancouver-bc-august-17-2012-david-black-owner-of-blac.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">111116-SUN_0817N_blackrefinery_357-1112_oped_black-W.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/75f45bf94e1e4e2bd2658b966c15a8e0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">henchin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>B.C. puts new, highly reflective paint on Metro Vancouver highways</title>
		<link>http://vancouversun.com/news/politics/b-c-puts-new-highly-reflective-paint-on-metro-vancouver-highways</link>
		<comments>http://vancouversun.com/news/politics/b-c-puts-new-highly-reflective-paint-on-metro-vancouver-highways#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 01:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Shaw]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BC Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coquihalla Highway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vancouversun.com/?p=798798</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[VICTORIA — Lower Mainland drivers will soon have an easier time seeing road lines on provincial highways, as the B.C. government begins to roll out new highly reflective paint. The Ministry of Transportation has begun painting more than 3,000 kilometres of roads in the Lower Mainland, Pemberton, Victoria and Duncan with a new specialized formula [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>VICTORIA</strong> — Lower Mainland drivers will soon have an easier time seeing road lines on provincial highways, as the B.C. government begins to roll out new highly reflective paint.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Transportation has begun painting more than 3,000 kilometres of roads in the Lower Mainland, Pemberton, Victoria and Duncan with a new specialized formula of paint that contains larger, higher-quality, reflective glass beads.</p>
<p>The beads will make it easier for drivers to see the yellow and white road lines when it&#8217;s dark and raining, and address long-standing concerns from municipalities that previous highway paint was hard-to-see and quick to wear off from the roads. Highway 1, the provincial highway that cuts through Metro Vancouver from Abbotsford to North Vancouver, will be one of the roads to get the new paint.</p>
<p>The changes are part of a $4-million boost to the ministry&#8217;s annual highway budget, which will help cover new, five-year maintenance contracts with private companies that will be required to paint 20 per cent more highway lines throughout the province, add second coats to areas where paint fades the quickest and better monitor the condition of highway paint on provincial roads.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s absolutely money well-spent,&#8221; said Transportation Minister Claire Trevena. &#8220;It’s a bottom-line safety thing. It&#8217;s worth the investment because it&#8217;s not going to just make people safe, but ensure they are driving more safely because they can see where the lanes are and where the edge of the road is.&#8221;</p>
<p>Disappearing highway lines has been one of the Ministry of Transportation&#8217;s <a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/b-c-hunts-for-a-durable-highway-line-paint" target="_blank" rel="noopener">top complaints since 2010</a> when Ottawa banned the oil-based highway paint commonly used by most provinces and <a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/politics/province-picks-new-high-durability-paint-for-highway-lines" target="_blank" rel="noopener">left them scrambling to find alternatives</a>.&nbsp;B.C. switched&nbsp;to a lower-pollution alkyd paint for coastal and northern roads, and a water-based&nbsp;paint in the Interior, but both were less durable and neither lasted an entire year.</p>
<p>Ministry officials then launched a search to develop new paint, settling after tests in 2017 on a new &#8220;high-build paint&#8221; that goes&nbsp;on extra thick to survive the tough winters, salt, chains and ploughs of B.C.’s Interior and north,&nbsp;and a “premium glass-bead” paint that&nbsp;provides reflection better suited to the wet coastal climate of Vancouver Island, the Mainland and the Sunshine Coast.</p>
<p>The glass-bead paint is being rolled out now. But the high-built paint failed its tests, after transportation crews had trouble getting it to stay at certain thickness levels exceeding 18 mils. Instead, the government has reverted back to applying its less-durable paint in two coats, which it says can be applied as thick as a total of 32 mils but is&nbsp;also a more costly and time-consuming process.</p>
<p>The government is currently accepting bids for new highway-maintenance contractors, and Trevena said they will be required to follow the new requirements for additional painting and second coats.</p>
<p>&#8220;Safety is No. 1 and I’ve already come on hard that we’ve got to make sure the contractors are doing the work,&#8221; said Trevena.</p>
<p>One of the province&#8217;s worst highways, the Coquihalla, will be a mixture of both paints — glass-bead paint for the wet roads along the southern portion of the highway toward Hope and the double-thick paint closer to the summit where it snows.</p>
<p>However, while the paint might provide some improvement, it isn&#8217;t expected to last an entire winter due to the fact that the extreme weather, snowploughs, chains, sand and studded tires actually strip away the asphalt on the road in addition to the paint.&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="mailto:rshaw@postmedia.com">rshaw@postmedia.com</a></p>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/robshaw_vansun">twitter.com/robshaw_vansun</a></p>
<p><em><a href="mailto:vanweb@postmedia.com">CLICK HERE</a> to report a typo. </em></p>
<p><em>Is there more to this story? We&#8217;d like to hear from you about this or any other stories you think we should know about. Email <a href="mailto:vantips@postmedia.com">vantips@postmedia.com</a>.</em>&lt;/p</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>You might also like:</strong></p>
<div class="pmYTPlayerContainer video-container"><div id="pn_video_141619"></div></div><script type="text/javascript">( function() { pnLoadVideo( "videos", "oSq1T5htwiI", "pn_video_141619", "", "", [] ); } )();</script>
<hr>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vancouversun.com/news/politics/b-c-puts-new-highly-reflective-paint-on-metro-vancouver-highways/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<postmedia:alexa><![CDATA[B.C. puts new, highly reflective paint on Metro Vancouver highways. VICTORIA — Lower Mainland drivers will soon have an easier time seeing road lines on provincial highways, as the B.C. government begins to roll out new highly reflective paint.]]></postmedia:alexa>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2016/05/line-painting-in-progress-for-a-story-by-rob-shaw-on-b-c-t.jpeg" />
		<media:content url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2016/05/line-painting-in-progress-for-a-story-by-rob-shaw-on-b-c-t.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">050616-0507_highway_lines_6523432637_6b9bc2a2bd_o.jpg-0507_highway_lines-W.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/60b5807e9f81dc19f89e4ef084ed2fe8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rfshaw</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dan Fumano: Private letter shows NPA process a &#039;kangaroo court,&#039; rejected mayoral hopeful says</title>
		<link>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/dan-fumano-private-letter-shows-npa-process-a-kangaroo-court-rejected-mayoral-hopeful-says</link>
		<comments>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/dan-fumano-private-letter-shows-npa-process-a-kangaroo-court-rejected-mayoral-hopeful-says#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 01:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Fumano]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Local News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2018 Municipal Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2018 Vancouver Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[City Hall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vancouver]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vancouversun.com/?p=798797</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Non-Partisan Association shot down their own sitting caucus member&#8217;s bid for its mayoral nomination because of, among other things, concerns that his day job left him in an &#8220;inherently conflicted&#8221; position. That allegation was among the &#8220;serious concerns&#8221; outlined in a two-page letter sent Sunday evening from NPA president Gregory Baker to NPA Coun. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Non-Partisan Association shot down their own sitting caucus member&#8217;s bid for its mayoral nomination because of, among other things, concerns that his day job left him in an &#8220;inherently conflicted&#8221; position.</p>
<p>That allegation was among the &#8220;serious concerns&#8221; outlined in a two-page letter sent Sunday evening from NPA president Gregory Baker to NPA Coun. Hector Bremner, according to a person who had reviewed the document.</p>
<p>But Bremner called that allegation &#8220;ridiculous&#8221; Monday, saying the correspondence only highlighted how the NPA&#8217;s mayoral nomination process has devolved into a &#8220;kangaroo court.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sunday&#8217;s letter came at the end of a tumultuous week for the city&#8217;s oldest political party, after the NPA&nbsp;<a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/npa-mayoral-candidate-hopeful-hector-bremner-rejected-by-party-board" target="_blank" rel="noopener">board voted last Monday</a> to reject Bremner&#8217;s attempt to seek the party&#8217;s mayoral nomination, prompting a series of departures from the party, including prospective candidates and two board members, as <a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/dan-fumano-very-very-strange-times-at-the-npa-as-rumours-swirl-and-directors-quit" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Postmedia News reported last Friday</a>. By Monday, another director had departed, bringing the total to three.</p>
<p>On Monday morning Baker released a statement saying he had sent a &#8220;confidential letter&#8221; to Bremner the previous evening, &#8220;outlining in detail the reasons why the NPA board did not approve his mayoral application.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Although the NPA does not plan to publicly release this information, Mr. Bremner is within his rights to release the information, as well as the contents of the letter, as he sees fit,&#8221; Baker said in the statement.</p>
<p>The letter hasn&#8217;t been released publicly, but a person who had a copy of it read excerpts to The Vancouver Sun over the phone Monday and described parts of it, including the list of the NPA&#8217;s concerns about Bremner&#8217;s application.</p>
<p>Within hours of Baker&#8217;s statement Monday morning, Bremner responded with a statement of his own, saying the concerns outlined in the letter were &#8220;based on politically motivated accusations made by a rival campaign, not on anything of substance.&#8221;</p>
<p>Bremner&#8217;s statement Monday morning said he would be &#8220;responding in the next few days to this letter and more importantly about our path forward.&#8221;</p>
<p>But later in the day, after Postmedia obtained information about the letter, informed Bremner of a plan to publish some of the details, and offered him a chance to respond, he granted a phone interview Monday afternoon.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ll obviously have a full response to the letter at some point, and it&#8217;s unfortunate that parts of it are going to get out, out of context,&#8221; Bremner said. &#8220;It took (the NPA) a week to write it, so it&#8217;s going to take me a day or so to respond &#8230; The letter only proves that it was a kangaroo court.&#8221;</p>
<p>The letter outlines the NPA&#8217;s &#8220;serious concerns&#8221; about Bremner&#8217;s application, beginning with Bremner&#8217;s request that his lawyer could accompany him to the Green Light Committee meeting to discuss his prospects of being on the ballot for the NPA&#8217;s nomination meeting May 29.</p>
<p>The letter cites three conflict-of-interest complaints involving Bremner&#8217;s work with the Pace Group, a media-relations and lobbying firm.&nbsp;Baker confirmed Monday that the three complaints referenced in the letter were those filed by two locals named Raza Mirza and Justin Fung.</p>
<p>Mirza and Fung, both of whom spoke <a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/dan-fumano-candidates-face-unanswered-questions-as-npa-mayoral-nomination-deadline-approaches" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last month to Postmedia</a> about their complaints, said they had recently signed up for NPA memberships. Both expressed concerns about Bremner&#8217;s suitability for the city&#8217;s top job.</p>
<p>But Bremner and his supporters say Mirza and Fung are motivated by their stated&nbsp;support for a rival candidate for this year&#8217;s NPA&#8217;s mayoral nomination, Glen Chernen. Last September,&nbsp;<a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/npa-nomination-contest-for-vancouver-seat-marked-by-controversy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chernen filed his own complaint</a>&nbsp;involving Bremner&#8217;s lobbying work, while the two were competing for&nbsp;the NPA council nomination for last October&#8217;s byelection, which Bremner won.&nbsp;</p>
<h2 class="cat-head short"><span>Related</span></h2>
<ul class="related_links"><li><a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/npa-calls-bremners-comments-tying-race-to-rejection-of-candidacy-defamatory">NPA calls Bremner&#039;s comments tying race to rejection of candidacy &#039;defamatory&#039;</a></li><li><a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/failed-npa-mayoral-candidate-hector-bremner-claims-race-played-role-in-his-rejection">Failed NPA mayoral candidate Hector Bremner claims race played role in his rejection</a></li><li><a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/npa-mayoral-candidate-hopeful-hector-bremner-rejected-by-party-board">NPA mayoral candidate hopeful Hector Bremner rejected by party board</a></li></ul>
<p>The NPA&#8217;s letter alleged Bremner is &#8220;inherently conflicted&#8221; because of his work with the Pace Group, and expressed concerns that the councillor wasn&#8217;t &#8220;forthright&#8221; in some of his responses to previous complaints.</p>
<p>Bremner said:&nbsp;<span style="font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">&#8220;It&#8217;s a ridiculous statement to say I&#8217;m inherently conflicted,&#8221; adding he </span>made it clear to the NPA that if he won the nomination he would quit his job with the Pace Group to campaign full-time, thereby eliminating the potential for conflict.</p>
<p>The final point of concern in the NPA&#8217;s letter said that Bremner &#8220;waffled&#8221; on the question of whether he would allow the board to control his policy direction if he were to win the party&#8217;s mayoral nomination.</p>
<p>The point about the &#8220;waffling,&#8221; Bremner said, &#8220;is really profound. My comments to (the NPA board) was saying I certainly wanted to work with them, but I also asked that the candidate&#8217;s positions be considered. Not just some shadow group that&#8217;s unelected and not public is somehow running government, essentially, if we were to form government. That, to me, is just exemplary of what we were contending with.&#8221;</p>
<p>Bremner was set to meet Monday night with a group, including organizers, advisers and possible council candidates, to discuss their plans for the October election. It&#8217;s expected Bremner will make an announcement in the next two or three days, with many observers believing he may end up running against the NPA with his own slate.</p>
<p><a href="mailto:dfumano@postmedia.com">dfumano@postmedia.com</a></p>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/fumano">twitter.com/fumano</a></p>
<p><em><a href="mailto:vanweb@postmedia.com">CLICK HERE</a> to report a typo. </em></p>
<p><em>Is there more to this story? We&#8217;d like to hear from you about this or any other stories you think we should know about. Email <a href="mailto:vantips@postmedia.com">vantips@postmedia.com</a>.</em>&lt;/p</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>You might also like:</strong></p>
<div class="pmYTPlayerContainer video-container"><div id="pn_video_267779"></div></div><script type="text/javascript">( function() { pnLoadVideo( "videos", "SyCBji0fzQI", "pn_video_267779", "", "", [] ); } )();</script>
<hr>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/dan-fumano-private-letter-shows-npa-process-a-kangaroo-court-rejected-mayoral-hopeful-says/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<postmedia:alexa><![CDATA[Dan Fumano: Private letter shows NPA process a 'kangaroo court,' rejected mayoral hopeful says. The Non-Partisan Association shot down their own sitting caucus member's bid for its mayoral nomination because of, among other things, concerns that his day job left him in an "inherently conflicted" position.]]></postmedia:alexa>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/png0508-14274-jpg.jpg" />
		<media:content url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/png0508-14274-jpg.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">051118-PNG0508__14274.JPG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/37830cbd16e23a9f2e1f300c3f45e9a2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">danfumanoprov</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>David Hughes: Politics versus the future: Canada’s Orwellian energy standoff</title>
		<link>http://vancouversun.com/opinion/op-ed/david-hughes-politics-versus-the-future-canadas-orwellian-energy-standoff</link>
		<comments>http://vancouversun.com/opinion/op-ed/david-hughes-politics-versus-the-future-canadas-orwellian-energy-standoff#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 01:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harvey Enchin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Op-Ed]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vancouversun.com/?p=795666</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[These are strange days, indeed. Our federal government, which has signed on to the Paris Agreement, has also come out swinging in support of the Trans Mountain pipeline expansion. And we continue to be told that increasing oil and gas production and meeting emissions reduction targets are mutually compatible goals. This thinking is also reflected [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These are strange days, indeed.</p>
<p>Our federal government, which has signed on to the Paris Agreement, has also come out swinging in support of the Trans Mountain pipeline expansion. And we continue to be told that increasing oil and gas production and meeting emissions reduction targets are mutually compatible goals.</p>
<p>This thinking is also reflected in Alberta’s ‘climate leadership plan,’ which allows oil sands emissions to grow by 40 per cent and places no restrictions on oil and gas production outside of the oil sands.</p>
<p>Even with that cap in place, National Energy Board oil and gas production projections show that upstream emission will increase enough that a 49 per-cent reduction in emissions from the rest of Canada’s economy will be required to meet our Paris targets.</p>
<p>Notwithstanding the difficulty in making such radical reductions in a short timeframe, Justin Trudeau and Rachel Notley have both dug in on the “need” to build the Trans Mountain pipeline expansion, going so far as to threaten that a failure to build the pipeline could result in Alberta’s extremely modest ‘climate leadership plan’ being cancelled.</p>
<p>Let’s examine this “need.” Even if oil and gas production is allowed to grow per the National Energy Board’s projections, there are two other approved export pipelines (Line 3 and Keystone XL), that without the&nbsp;Trans Mountain pipeline expansion would provide sufficient pipeline export capacity for foreseeable production growth, and access to world prices on the Gulf Coast.</p>
<p>The oft-repeated ‘Canada has only one market’ rhetoric ignores the fact that oil is a globally priced commodity, that the U.S. Gulf Coast has the world’s largest concentration of coking refineries able to optimally refine Canadian heavy oil, and that there is likely a price discount, not a premium, from exporting to Asia, given transportation costs.</p>
<p>But building any of these pipelines ignores the fact that upstream oil and gas emissions under Alberta’s plan, given&nbsp;National Energy Board projections, will account for more than three quarters (76 per cent) of Canada’s emissions by 2040 and 100 per cent by 2050—if emissions reduction targets are to be met.</p>
<p>Some environmental groups assert that it will be relatively easy to swap out fossil fuels for renewable energy—wind, solar, biomass, biofuels and geothermal energy. That is unlikely given the scale of such a transition. Renewable energy can certainly be scaled up a lot, along with geothermal energy for heating and cooling, but we will likely need fossil fuels for decades to come as we make the transition.</p>
<p>That’s because solar and wind are intermittent, on an hourly and seasonal basis, and the energy they produce &#8211; electricity &#8211; makes up only 17 per cent of current delivered energy in Canada.</p>
<p>They need to be backed up by dispatchable sources like natural gas, or with storage, to provide reliable power. Solar and wind now provide less than 5 per cent of Canada’s electricity generation, and much less of total delivered energy.</p>
<p>All of which means we can’t make the transition overnight, and the longer we delay, the more difficult it will become. It also means we can’t simply plan to swap one source of plentiful energy for another, without reducing consumption. Mass transit, building codes, building retrofits and other efficiencies will be important.</p>
<p>Industry extracts the lowest-cost, highest-quality, least emissions-intensive fossil fuel resources first. Knowing that fossil fuels will likely be needed for a long time to come, and that producing them is very emissions-intensive, Canada’s current de facto strategy of selling them off at rock bottom prices with declining revenues to government makes little sense.</p>
<p>Governments telling us we must increase emissions from oil and gas production in order to meet emissions reduction targets would make George Orwell proud. Canada needs a viable energy strategy that will meet long-term energy security needs and emissions reduction commitments. Investments in political capital, to the exclusion of common sense and a view beyond the next election, seem to have relegated us to Orwell’s world.</p>
<p>David Hughes is an earth scientist and author of ‘Canada’s Energy Outlook: current realities and implications for a carbon-constrained future’ co-published by the Canadian Centre for Policy Alternatives, Corporate Mapping Project and Parkland Institute, and available at <a href="http://energyoutlook.ca">energyoutlook.ca</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vancouversun.com/opinion/op-ed/david-hughes-politics-versus-the-future-canadas-orwellian-energy-standoff/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<postmedia:alexa><![CDATA[David Hughes: Politics versus the future: Canada’s Orwellian energy standoff. These are strange days, indeed.]]></postmedia:alexa>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/1116-biz-gmo-suncor.jpg" />
		<media:content url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/1116-biz-gmo-suncor.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">050818-1116_biz_gmo_suncor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/75f45bf94e1e4e2bd2658b966c15a8e0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">henchin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vaughn Palmer: NDP, B.C. Hydro forced to go it alone in Site C fight after feds back away</title>
		<link>http://vancouversun.com/opinion/columnists/vaughn-palmer-ndp-and-b-c-hydro-forced-to-go-it-alone-in-site-c-fight-after-feds-back-away</link>
		<comments>http://vancouversun.com/opinion/columnists/vaughn-palmer-ndp-and-b-c-hydro-forced-to-go-it-alone-in-site-c-fight-after-feds-back-away#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stephen Snelgrove]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Columnists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BC NDP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kinder Morgan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Site C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vaughn Palmer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vancouversun.com/?p=798781</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[VICTORIA — The New Democrats maintained Monday that Ottawa’s scaling down of its share of the legal battle over Site C was not a surprise payback for B.C.’s legalistic foot-dragging on the Trans Mountain pipeline. “They did let us know,” Energy Minister Michelle Mungall told reporters when asked about the federal decision not to contest [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>VICTORIA — The New Democrats maintained Monday that Ottawa’s scaling down of its share of the legal battle over Site C was not a surprise payback for B.C.’s legalistic foot-dragging on the Trans Mountain pipeline.</p>
<p>“They did let us know,” Energy Minister Michelle Mungall told reporters when asked about the federal decision not to contest a First Nation’s application for an injunction to halt construction of the giant hydroelectric dam on the Peace River.</p>
<p>The federal decision, filed quietly in B.C. Supreme Court last week, raised suspicions that Ottawa was playing tit for tat on the Trans Mountain expansion, which it supports and the B.C. government opposes.</p>
<p>Two days before Ottawa filed its notice on Site C, the province was in the B.C. Court of Appeal seeking approval to regulate increased movement of Alberta bitumen via pipeline and or rail.</p>
<p>But Mungall denied the federal government was leaving the province to fend for itself on Site C. The federal government remains committed to defending its approval of Site C in the broader court proceeding where the West Moberly First Nation claims the project violates its treaty rights.</p>
<p>“From our perspective the federal government is not particularly involved with this aspect of the court case,” said Mungall. “So them not getting involved specifically with the injunction I don’t find too surprising.”</p>
<p>“They are going to be defending the overall permits,” she said, referring to a pair of permits issued by the Trudeau government in the summer of 2016 allowing construction activity to intrude into the Peace River.</p>
<p>Backstopping the minister, her office later distributed copies of a statement put out Monday by the federal ministry of environment and climate change.</p>
<p>“The injunction motion is an interim procedural step that relates specifically to the construction phase of the Site C project, which falls under the purview of the province of B.C. and B.C. Hydro,” it said.</p>
<p>“While we aren’t intervening in this interim procedural step, Canada will defend its environmental assessment and Crown consultation processes, as well as all federally issued permits, in the main legal action, which is anticipated for the end of 2019.”</p>
<p>The federal environment approval certificate was issued by the previous Harper government in 2014, clearing the way for the start of construction in the summer of 2015.</p>
<p>“When we formed government,” continued the statement from the Trudeau government, “we implemented interim principles for environmental assessments that include a commitment not to revisit projects that have already been reviewed and approved. Our government will ensure every condition attached to the approval of the Site C project is met, and conduct regular inspections to ensure compliance.”</p>
<p>Site C has already been hit with directives from federal and provincial regulators to deal with sediment pouring into the Peace River from construction on the unstable banks.</p>
<p>Ottawa professes confidence that in the larger treaty case, West Moberly will not succeed in overturning federal approvals. “The federal environmental assessment process for the Site C project has already been upheld in other court actions,” said the statement, which is also the case with provincial approvals as well.</p>
<p>But Ottawa’s decision to not contest the injunction application means the province and B.C. Hydro will have to carry that part of the legal action themselves.</p>
<p>The stakes will be enormous for B.C.</p>
<p>More than $2 billion has already been spent on the project, and hundreds of millions more committed in construction contracts. As of the most recent report from B.C. Hydro, more than 2,000 people were working on the project.</p>
<p>An injunction to halt construction pending resolution of the treaty claim would mean massive layoffs and another escalation in the estimated cost of a project budget already approaching $11 billion.</p>
<p>But the stakes for the First Nation are large as well. West Moberly asks the court to weigh the damage done to its treaty rights and traditional territory by the previous W.A.C. Bennett and Peace Canyon dams, as well as Site C.</p>
<p>Construction to date of the third dam has already exacted a sizable toll on the river banks and surrounding terrain, and that’s before the commencement of the river diversion, construction of the dam itself and then the filling of the reservoir behind it.</p>
<p>Hence the First Nation application for an injunction to halt construction, pending a full airing of a case that could produce a court order to terminate the project and/or compensate West Moberly for treaty infringement.</p>
<p>Ottawa’s announcement that it won’t challenge the injunction application led to calls for B.C. to do the same.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Not likely, in my estimation. But Mungall did appear to leave the door open when asked if the province would continue to fight the injunction. “As far as I know to date,” she replied.</p>
<p>Was that a hint at a willingness to alter the construction schedule to reduce the impact on West Moberly territory pending the outcome of the court proceedings?</p>
<p>The river diversion is not scheduled to start until the fall of 2020, followed by construction of the dam. Filling the reservoir is set for late 2023, more than five years from now. That might allow enough time to a expedite outcome of the treaty case without needing full blown halt to construction.</p>
<p>Sheer speculation. At this point, when the hearing on the injunction application begins in B.C. Supreme Court on July 23, the province and B.C. Hydro will be going it alone.</p>
<p><a href="mailto:vpalmer@postmedia.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">vpalmer@postmedia.com</a></p>
<p><em><a href="mailto:vanweb@postmedia.com">CLICK HERE</a> to report a typo. </em></p>
<p><em>Is there more to this story? We&#8217;d like to hear from you about this or any other stories you think we should know about. Email <a href="mailto:vantips@postmedia.com">vantips@postmedia.com</a>.</em></p>
<hr>
<p><strong>You might also like:</strong></p>
<div class="pmYTPlayerContainer video-container"><div id="pn_video_185659"></div></div><script type="text/javascript">( function() { pnLoadVideo( "videos", "SyCBji0fzQI", "pn_video_185659", "", "", [] ); } )();</script>
<hr>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vancouversun.com/opinion/columnists/vaughn-palmer-ndp-and-b-c-hydro-forced-to-go-it-alone-in-site-c-fight-after-feds-back-away/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<postmedia:alexa><![CDATA[Vaughn Palmer: NDP, B.C. Hydro forced to go it alone in Site C fight after feds back away. VICTORIA — The New Democrats maintained Monday that Ottawa’s scaling down of its share of the legal battle over Site C was not a surprise payback for B.C.’s legalistic foot-dragging on the Trans Mountain pipeline.]]></postmedia:alexa>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/batch-plant-area-on-the-south-bank-november-2017-jpg.jpg" />
		<media:content url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/batch-plant-area-on-the-south-bank-november-2017-jpg.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">051418-Batch_plant_area_on_the_south_bank_(November_2017)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6ea6cd653a6982c9f8f6d1adb9773ff1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ssnelgrove</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vancouver Sun series on securities regulation failures nominated for journalism award</title>
		<link>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/vancouver-sun-series-on-securities-regulation-failures-nominated-for-journalism-award</link>
		<comments>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/vancouver-sun-series-on-securities-regulation-failures-nominated-for-journalism-award#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick Johnston]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Local News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BC Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[British Columbia Securities Commission]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vancouversun.com/?p=799196</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A Vancouver Sun and Province reporter&#8217;s work exposing the failures of Canadian security regulators and governments in collecting more than a half-billion dollars in financial penalties is up for national recognition. Gordon Hoekstra&#8217;s 2017 series on financial crime — called&#160;Stealing Away — is one of six nominees for the Michener Award, which recognizes &#8220;meritorious public [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Vancouver Sun and Province reporter&#8217;s work exposing the failures of Canadian security regulators and governments in collecting more than a half-billion dollars in financial penalties is up for national recognition.</p>
<p><span style="font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Gordon Hoekstra&#8217;s 2017 series on financial crime — called&nbsp;Stealing Away — is one of six nominees for the Michener Award, which recognizes &#8220;</span>meritorious public service journalism.&#8221;</p>
<p>Using databases created from a decade’s worth of penalty status reports, court records and other reports, the series revealed that more than a half a billion dollars in B.C. Securities Commission penalties had gone unpaid and jail time for fraudsters in B.C. was a rarity.</p>
<p>In response, B.C. Finance Minister Carole James ordered the Securities commission to improve its collections and enforcement and also said she expected a greater focus on criminal prosecution.</p>
<p>The commission also began taking steps to be able to seize property and goods of financial fraudsters who owe nearly $70 million in unpaid penalties from the past decade.</p>
<p>&#8220;Journalists must be dogged in their pursuit of the truth and unflinching in their storytelling. Gord Hoekstra displayed both these traits in his investigation of uncollected penalties levied by security regulators in B.C.,&#8221; said Harold Munro, editor-in-chief for The Vancouver Sun and The Province.</p>
<p>&#8220;I’m grateful to the Michener Awards Foundation for recognizing Gord and The Vancouver Sun with such a prestigious nomination. There is no higher honour in Canadian journalism.&#8221;</p>
<h2 class="cat-head short"><span>Related</span></h2>
<ul class="related_links"><li><a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/fraudsters-in-b-c-rarely-face-police-investigation-or-jail-time">Stealing Away: Fraudsters in B.C. rarely face police investigation or jail time</a></li><li><a href="http://vancouversun.com/business/local-business/hundreds-of-millions-of-penalties-issued-by-b-c-securities-commission-going-unpaid">Stealing Away: Hundreds of millions of penalties issued by B.C. Securities Commission going unpaid</a></li><li><a href="http://vancouversun.com/business/local-business/condo-case-shows-difficulty-b-c-securities-commission-has-collecting-fines">Stealing Away: Fraudster’s condo transfer to wife shows difficulty B.C. securities commission has collecting fines</a></li><li><a href="http://vancouversun.com/business/local-business/b-c-government-expects-changes-in-2018-to-help-collect-fraud-penalties-pursue-criminal-convictions">B.C. government expects changes in 2018 to help collect fraud penalties, pursue criminal convictions</a></li></ul>
<p>The other finalists are from Cogeco Media, CBC Edmonton, Global News, the Globe and Mail, and the Toronto Star.</p>
<p>The winner will be announced by the Governor General at a ceremony at Rideau Hall in Ottawa on June 12.</p>
<p>The Michener Award, founded in 1970 by the late Roland Michener, then governor general, honours excellence in public-service journalism. The judges’ decisions are heavily influenced by the degree of public benefit generated by the print, broadcast and online entries submitted for consideration.</p>
<p>Recognizing outstanding and unbiased public service in journalism, the award is presented to news organizations rather than to individuals: newspapers, broadcasting stations and networks, news agencies, periodicals, magazines and online journalism sources.</p>
<p><a href="mailto:pjohnston@postmedia.com">pjohnston@postmedia.com</a></p>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/risingaction" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com/risingaction</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/vancouver-sun-series-on-securities-regulation-failures-nominated-for-journalism-award/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<postmedia:alexa><![CDATA[Vancouver Sun series on securities regulation failures nominated for journalism award. A Vancouver Sun and Province reporter's work exposing the failures of Canadian security regulators and governments in collecting more than a half-billion dollars in financial penalties is up for national recognition.]]></postmedia:alexa>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2017/12/mg_chad-03-jpg1.jpg" />
		<media:content url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2017/12/mg_chad-03-jpg1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">121517-_MG_CHAD-03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/698b81e98ea980c17ba35cb3f359980f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pjohnstonprov</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Southern B.C. bracing for second round of flooding as snowpacks melt</title>
		<link>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/southern-b-c-bracing-for-second-round-of-flooding-as-snowpacks-melt</link>
		<comments>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/southern-b-c-bracing-for-second-round-of-flooding-as-snowpacks-melt#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cassidy Olivier]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Local News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vancouversun.com/?p=799138</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Flood-weary residents in communities across B.C.&#8217;s Interior are bracing for the possibility of yet another round of evacuations as a result of high temperatures and rapid snowmelt. Chris Duffy of Emergency Management B.C. said about 2,000 homes are subject to evacuation orders —&#160;nearly 1,500 of those are in the Kootenay-Boundary Regional District. More than 2,600 [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Flood-weary residents in communities across B.C.&#8217;s Interior are bracing for the possibility of yet another round of evacuations as a result of high temperatures and rapid snowmelt.</p>
<p>Chris Duffy of Emergency Management B.C. said about 2,000 homes are subject to evacuation orders —&nbsp;nearly 1,500 of those are in the Kootenay-Boundary Regional District. More than 2,600 other homes are under evacuation alert throughout the province.</p>
<p>Many parts of the province are seeing temperatures six degrees above the average for this time of year, increasing the speed of which snowpacks are melting.</p>
<p>David Campbell, head of the B.C. River Forecast Centre, said there’s uncertainty as to what areas will be affected the most by floods as unseasonable heat and the potential for rain hits the province in the next seven to 10 days.</p>
<p>“Clearly this is an extremely intense weather system in terms of the temperatures, and certainly coming at a time in the season where rivers are already flowing very high,” he said.</p>
<p>Campbell also warned that rapidly rising flows in the Fraser Valley could surmount to historic levels by this weekend, expected to reach almost 12,000 cubic metres per second in Hope — the highest levels since 1948.</p>
<p>Steady rises in the Fraser River have stretched from the Headwaters to the Lower Mainland, however no flood advisories are currently in effect for the region.</p>
<p>The areas of highest concern for flooding are the Okanagan, Boundary, Shuswap, and the Similkameen Valley, where Duffy said they’ve “already experienced significant challenges.”</p>
<p>Uncertainty also looms for some communities in Southern B.C., who are recovering from last week&#8217;s floods.</p>
<p>Osoyoos Mayor Sue McKortoff said 53 residents have already evacuated, but said that number may increase significantly.</p>
<p>“We’re sort of stable right now, but the river is probably going to raise quite a bit,” she said. “It’s been recommended that they take precautions and get ready, because we’re not really sure where we’re headed.”</p>
<p>Tulameen Mayor Bob Coyne said many residents have just returned home, but may soon be required to leave once again.</p>
<p>“It’s a sit-and-wait kind of game,” Coyne said. “You can still see snow wherever you look here. With this weather, it’s got to go down eventually.”</p>
<p>Other areas that could see rising water levels include Prince George, Quesnel, and the Bulkley lakes district.</p>
<p>Emergency operation crews in the Regional District of Kootenay Boundary — which includes Grand Forks, B.C., one of the hardest hit areas —&nbsp;are on the ground working to fortify infrastructures that were damaged by earlier floods.</p>
<p>Chris Marsh, director of the Emergency Operations Centre for the Regional District of Kootenay Boundary, said floods have already had catastrophic damage in areas like Grand Forks.</p>
<p>“Protecting weakened infrastructure is their first priority,” Marsh said. “Things like electrical, sewage and water systems are all things we’re working on.”</p>
<p>The Regional District of Okanagan-Similkameen said in a news release that residents of Hedley, the village of Keremeos, and those living along the banks of the Similkameen River should prepare for an imminent evacuation order, and people with medical conditions, mobility issues, and those with livestock or animals should evacuate immediately.</p>
<p><em>with files from Canadian Press</em></p>
<p><a href="bmahichi@postmedia.com">bmahichi@postmedia.com</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/southern-b-c-bracing-for-second-round-of-flooding-as-snowpacks-melt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<postmedia:alexa><![CDATA[Southern B.C. bracing for second round of flooding as snowpacks melt. Flood-weary residents in communities across B.C.'s Interior are bracing for the possibility of yet another round of evacuations as a result of high temperatures and rapid snowmelt.]]></postmedia:alexa>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/flooding-bc-201805132.jpg" />
		<media:content url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/flooding-bc-201805132.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">051418-Flooding_BC_20180513</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/00367c3841b0ff76190297b5da51fe7c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cassidyolivierprov</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Squamish Chief Ian Campbell to run as a Vision Vancouver mayoral candidate</title>
		<link>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/squamish-chief-ian-campbell-to-run-as-a-vision-vancouver-mayoral-candidate</link>
		<comments>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/squamish-chief-ian-campbell-to-run-as-a-vision-vancouver-mayoral-candidate#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Local News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2018 Municipal Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2018 Vancouver Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vancouver]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vancouversun.com/?p=798870</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lingering hopes that Vancouver&#8217;s left-leaning parties can unite behind a single mayoral candidate may have taken a hit following Ian Campbell&#8217;s announcement on Monday that he will be taking a run at city council&#8217;s top job. Campbell, the hereditary chief of the Squamish Nation, is seeking the nomination of Vision Vancouver, which until Monday did [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lingering hopes that Vancouver&#8217;s left-leaning parties can unite behind a single mayoral candidate may have taken a hit following Ian Campbell&#8217;s announcement on Monday that he will be taking a run at city council&#8217;s top job.</p>
<p>Campbell, the hereditary chief of the Squamish Nation, is seeking the nomination of Vision Vancouver, which until Monday did not have a single candidate with a declared interest in succeeding outgoing mayor Gregor Robertson.</p>
<p>Were Campbell to get the party nod, that would pit him against at least two other candidates seeking&nbsp;office on the left — independents Shauna Sylvester and Kennedy Stewart.</p>
<p>Others continue to test the waters, but none have declared. Vision Councillor Raymond Louie is now among those who have decided against a mayoral run.</p>
<p>Mario Canseco,&nbsp;a Research Co.&nbsp;<span style="font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">pollster, said Campbell&#8217;s announcement complicates the race for left votes.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;For a while, we were talking about a &#8216;Unite the Left&#8217; effort that had no Vision Vancouver contenders,&#8221; he said. &#8220;This could potentially place a little bit of a bent in the negotiations because Vision might want to go it alone and essentially not deal with anyone else who might want to unite the left.&#8221;</p>
<p>Canseco said he has never ran numbers on Campbell, but noted that he may have an advantage over other Vision hopefuls, should any come forward. A win by Campbell would be a major milestone in that he would become the first-ever Indigenous mayor of B.C.&#8217;s largest city.</p>
<p>Drummers and dancers heralded Campbell&#8217;s announcement speech, in which he positioned himself as a unifier and a bridge builder.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is a difficult moment in our city&#8217;s history. Everywhere I go, people have been sharing their concerns about things they care about. They&#8217;re worried if they have a seat in the canoe and if their interests will be heard,&#8221; he said, speaking of the ability for people to live and thrive in Vancouver.</p>
<p>&#8220;As the next mayor of Vancouver, I will not rest until people who work hard and play by the rules can afford to live in your Vancouver again.&#8221;</p>
<p>Campbell said housing would be a key focus of his campaign. Affordability, job creation, climate change and homelessness were also priorities.</p>
<p>A news release issued by Campbell&#8217;s staff invited &#8220;all progressives&#8221; — regardless of party affiliation — to find a home with his campaign.</p>
<p>Campbell does have hurdles to overcome in his mayoral bid — foremost may be the fact that he lives in North Vancouver.</p>
<p>Ginger Gosnell-Myers, his campaign manager, said Campbell is now looking for a home to rent in Vancouver, where he has lived during different periods of his life. Campbell&#8217;s Squamish name, Xalek, &#8220;descends from the Xatslanexw Family, whom Vancouverites today know as Kitsilano,&#8221; Gosnell-Myers said.</p>
<p>&#8220;Vancouver has always been Ian&#8217;s home. …&nbsp;It is because of this deep-rooted connection that he decided to run,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>Campbell is a board member of <a href="http://mstdevelopment.ca/current-initiatives/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MST Development Corp.</a>, a&nbsp;<span style="font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Musqueam, Squamish and Tsleil-Waututh partnership&nbsp;</span><span style="font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">with&nbsp;a proclaimed 160-or-so acres of developable land. MST&#8217;s fully or partially owned Vancouver properties are the Jericho Lands, the Heather Street Lands, and a former Liquor Distribution Branch site on East Broadway that is co-owned with Aquilini Investment Group, according to the partnership.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Among those in Campbell&#8217;s corner is Andrea Reimer, a Vision councillor.</span></p>
<p>Michael Haack, a Vision Vancouver co-chair, would not say how many prospective candidates intend to contest for the party&#8217;s nomination, but said he looked forward to a robust nomination process that would end with a vote on June 24.</p>
<p><a href="mailto:mrobinson@postmedia.com">mrobinson@postmedia.com</a></p>
<hr>
<p><strong>You might also like:</strong></p>
<div class="pmYTPlayerContainer video-container"><div id="pn_video_117603"></div></div><script type="text/javascript">( function() { pnLoadVideo( "videos", "SyCBji0fzQI", "pn_video_117603", "", "", [] ); } )();</script>
<hr>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/squamish-chief-ian-campbell-to-run-as-a-vision-vancouver-mayoral-candidate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<postmedia:alexa><![CDATA[Squamish Chief Ian Campbell to run as a Vision Vancouver mayoral candidate. Lingering hopes that Vancouver's left-leaning parties can unite behind a single mayoral candidate may have taken a hit following Ian Campbell's announcement on Monday that he will be taking a run at city council's top job.]]></postmedia:alexa>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/png0514n-ian-campbell-03.jpg" />
		<media:content url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/png0514n-ian-campbell-03.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ian Campbell</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/593e2ea1ab0593759bb6cbb47778482a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mattrobinsonsun</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Former Delta CAO George Harvie plans run for mayor&#039;s seat</title>
		<link>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/former-delta-cao-george-harvie-plans-run-for-mayors-seat</link>
		<comments>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/former-delta-cao-george-harvie-plans-run-for-mayors-seat#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 23:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Saltman]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Local News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2018 Delta Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2018 Municipal Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Municipal government]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vancouversun.com/?p=799012</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Delta’s recently retired chief administrative officer is preparing a run for the mayor’s seat. George Harvie officially stepped down from his job as top bureaucrat — a job that he held for 18 years — on May 7, noting on social media that he was “looking forward to a change, but I won’t be going [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Delta’s recently retired chief administrative officer is preparing a run for the mayor’s seat.</p>
<p class="p1">George Harvie officially stepped down from his job as top bureaucrat — a job that he held for 18 years — on May 7, noting on social media that he was “looking forward to a change, but I won’t be going far.”</p>
<p class="p1">Harvie will run as part of a slate called Achieving for Delta, alongside five council candidates.</p>
<p class="p1">“The team name acknowledges George’s past achievements, and bridges his slate’s future achievements and continuing his record for success,” campaign team spokesman Micah Haince said.</p>
<p class="p1">Information about the other candidates on the slate will be revealed at an event at Tsawwassen Springs on May 22.</p>
<p class="p1">Mayor Lois Jackson has indicated that this is her last term and she will not seek re-election in the fall, leaving the seat vacant for the first time in almost two decades.</p>
<p class="p1">Jackson was elected mayor in 1999, after serving 26 years as a councillor. She was the first woman elected as councillor in Delta and the municipality’s second female mayor.</p>
<p class="p1">Harvie isn’t the first person to consider a mayoral run in Delta.</p>
<p class="p1">In March, Coun. Sylvia Bishop, who is serving her second term on council, announced that she would be running for mayor. She is part of a new slate called Team Delta, which includes Coun. Robert Campbell and three newcomers.</p>
<p class="p1"><a href="mailto:jensaltman@postmedia.com">jensaltman@postmedia.com</a></p>
<p class="p1"><a href="http://twitter.com/jensaltman" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com/jensaltman</a></p>
<p><em><a href="mailto:vanweb@postmedia.com">CLICK HERE</a> to report a typo. </em></p>
<p><em>Is there more to this story? We&#8217;d like to hear from you about this or any other stories you think we should know about. Email <a href="mailto:vantips@postmedia.com">vantips@postmedia.com</a>.</em>&lt;/p</p>
<h2 class="cat-head short"><span>Related</span></h2>
<ul class="related_links"><li><a href="http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/metro-vancouver-could-see-massive-turnover-of-mayors-in-fall-election">Metro Vancouver could see massive turnover of mayors in fall election</a></li></ul>
<hr>
<p><strong>You might also like:</strong></p>
<div class="pmYTPlayerContainer video-container"><div id="pn_video_59960"></div></div><script type="text/javascript">( function() { pnLoadVideo( "videos", "BI0kHmfno2c", "pn_video_59960", "", "", [] ); } )();</script>
<hr>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/former-delta-cao-george-harvie-plans-run-for-mayors-seat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<postmedia:alexa><![CDATA[Former Delta CAO George Harvie plans run for mayor's seat. Delta’s recently retired chief administrative officer is preparing a run for the mayor’s seat.
George Harvie officially stepped down from his job as top bureaucrat — a job that he held for 18 years — on May 7, noting on social media that he was “looking forward to a change, but I won’t be going far.”
Harvie will run as part of a slate called Achieving for Delta, alongside five council candidates.
“The team name acknowledges George’s past achievements, and bridges his slate’s future achievements and continuing his record for success,” campaign team spokesman Micah Haince said.
Information about the other candidates on the slate will be revealed at an event at Tsawwassen Springs on May 22.
Mayor Lois Jackson has indicated that this is her last term and she will not seek re-election in the fall, leaving the seat vacant for the first time in almost two decades.
Jackson was elected mayor in 1999, after serving 26 years as a councillor. She was the first woman elected as councillor in Delta and the municipality’s second female mayor.
Harvie isn’t the first person to consider a mayoral run in Delta.
In March, Coun. Sylvia Bishop, who is serving her second term on council, announced that she would be running for mayor. She is part of a new slate called Team Delta, which includes Coun. Robert Campbell and three newcomers.
jensaltman@postmedia.com
twitter.com/jensaltman
CLICK HERE to report a typo.]]></postmedia:alexa>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/harvie-jpg.jpg" />
		<media:content url="http://wpmedia.vancouversun.com/2018/05/harvie-jpg.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">George Harvie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/af8dd912b156da1e63a12345ce44da88?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jensaltman</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
